total.com 2019-12-01

# Privacy | total.com

Welcome to the website [https://www.total.com](https://www.total.com/) (the “website”). By connecting to or browsing the website, you agree that you have read, understood and accepted, without limitation or reservation, the personal data and cookies management policy (the “policy”) and our terms and conditions of use. Please note that other terms and conditions and personal data protection policies apply to other Total Group websites, and we recommend that you read them carefully.

The policy aims to inform you of the rights and freedoms that you can exercise in respect of our use of your personal data and describes the measures that we take to protect these data.

Total S.A is the “data controller” with responsibility for processing the personal data used to manage the website. These processing operations are carried out in accordance with the applicable law.

**1.  PURPOSE OF PROCESSING, LEGAL BASIS, THE PERIOD OF STORAGE AND TYPES OF DATA COLLECTED**

When you visit the website, you may need to provide us with a number of items of personal data, such as your first name and surname, in order to use the services available.

The data controller processes your personal data for the purposes of providing the services and for its legitimate interest.

In particular, we may collect some items of your personal data for the purposes of external communication in order to answer your requests for information.

In our online forms, the mandatory fields are marked with an asterisk. If you do not provide answers to the mandatory questions, we will not be able to provide you with the service(s) requested.

Your personal data will not be processed subsequently in a way that is incompatible with the purposes described above or below the collection forms. Your data are kept for no longer than necessary for processing.

**2.  RECIPIENTS OF DATA**

Your personal data may be communicated to one or more of the data controller's departments or to Total Group companies and one or more partners, independent distributors or subcontractors for the purposes of analysis and surveys.

If you leave a comment intended to be posted online, we may be required to publish some of your personal data on the website. Given the characteristics of the internet, namely the unrestricted capture of published data and the fact that it is difficult, or even impossible, to control how third parties can use these data, we hereby inform you that you can object to this publication by contacting us as explained in article 5 below.

Any transfer of data to a country outside the European Economic Area shall be carried out in accordance with the applicable regulations and in such a way as to protect your data appropriately. 

For the purposes of the services provided on this website, your data may be transferred to recipients located outside the European Union.

For this reason, the Total Group has adopted “Binding Corporate Rules” (BCR) governing intra-Group transfers of personal data originating in the European Economic Area. 

For data transfers not covered by the BCR, to countries outside the European Economic Area, other guarantees are provided. 

You can request a copy by contacting us as explained in article 5 below.

**3.  DATA SECURITY AND CONFIDENTIALITY**

The data controller takes appropriate steps to preserve the security and confidentiality of your personal data, including to prevent them from being distorted, damaged or disclosed to unauthorised third parties.

**4\. COOKIE  MANAGEMENT**

**4.1 Principle**

A cookie is a file which enables a website to save information relating to your computer’s browsing of the website (e.g. number of visits, number of pages viewed, etc.), to make your visits to the website smoother.

You can at any time delete the cookies stored on your computer, object to the storage of new cookies and receive a notification before new cookies are stored by changing your browser settings using the instructions below (“Types of cookies, cookies and statistics, and settings”). 

**Please note that if you remove a cookie or object to the storage of cookies on your device, you may not be able to use some of the website's services.  **

**4.2 Types of cookies, cookies and statistics and settings**

The cookies that may be stored on your server when you browse the website are cookies which are intended solely to enable or facilitate electronic communication or which are strictly necessary to provide the service you are requesting (language cookies, login cookies, etc.), or statistics cookies or other cookies in accordance with the conditions below.

When cookies require **your agreement before they can be saved** , we ask you for this agreement via the “find out more” link displayed on the first page of the website that you land on, in **which it is made clear that by continuing to browse the website you accept these cookies.  **

**4.2.1 Which cookies are stored?**

**• Data Controller cookies**

Cookie | Description | How to optout ? | Persistence  
---|---|---|---  
Site (has_js) | Contains information about the browser session and allows visitors to log into the website | See article 4.2.2 | Removed when the browser is closed  
Site (cookie_agreed) | Remembers a visitor's choice regarding cookies | See article 4.2.2 | 13 months   
  
**• Third parties cookies**

Cookie editor | Description | How to optout ? | Persistence  
---|---|---|---  
Score Card Research Beacon | Allows Share this to see how many visitors come to the site | 

<http://www.sharethis.com/privacy>

 click on the “Opt Out” button for advertising cookies or see article 4.2.2

| 2 years  
ShareThis | Allows sharing on Miscellaneous Social platforms | 

<http://www.sharethis.com/privacy>

 click on the “Opt Out” button for advertising cookies or see article 4.2.2

| 

__unam (9 months)

__stdlxmap (7 days)

__stgmap (7 days)

__stid (24hours)

__uset (24hours)

STPC (24hours)  
  
METRIXLAB

| Allows and records the opening of the satisfaction form about the site | Please contact [privacy@MetrixLab.com](mailto:privacy@MetrixLab.com) or see article 4.2.2 | 7 months  
FASTFONT | Allows to improve the display of contents | See article 4.2.2 | Removed when the browser is closed  
TWITTER | Records ID’s for sharing on twitter | Through your profile, go to your Security Settings page and uncheck the box under the promoted content section or see article 4.2.2 | 18 months  
FACEBOOK | Records ID’s for sharing on facebook | 

<https://www.datalogix.com/privacy/>

scroll down to the "Choice" heading, click the last "click here" link in the paragraph, and fill in your information or  see article 4.2.2

| 2 years   
  
**• Statistics cookies**

Cookie editor | Description | How to optout ? | Persistence  
---|---|---|---  
  
AT INTERNET

idrxvr  

tmst

| 

Allows to see how many visitors come to the site and how often

| <http://www.xiti.com/en/optout.aspx> or see article 4.2.2 | 7 months  
  
Statistics cookies are used to measure the number of visits, the number of pages viewed, users’ activity on the website and how often they return. The statistics tool used generates a cookie with a unique identifier, which is stored for no longer than. Your IP address is also collected in order to determine the town/city from which you are accessing the website. This is immediately anonymised after use so that you cannot be identified as a natural person. The statistical data on website visits are collected by the providers AT Internet and Google Analytics and subsequently transferred to the data controller in an aggregated and anonymised form in a web interface to which it alone has access. The data collected are not transferred to third parties or used for other purposes. You can block those cookies by using the “opt out” proceeding above <http://www.xiti.com/en/optout.aspx> and <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/181881?hl=en>.

**4.2.2.  How do you delete cookies, receive notification of their storage or change your browser settings?**

**•  How do you delete cookies already stored on your computer?**

  * On your workstation;
  * On the C:\ drive select the Windows folder;
  * Open the “temporary internet Files” folder;
  * Select all the files (CTRL A); 
  * Choose the “delete” option; 

**•  How do you change browser settings to reject or be informed of the storage of cookies?**

  * In the Internet Explorer 5 (Microsoft) browser: Select “Tools”, and then “Internet Options”. Click on the “Security” tab, then “Custom level” and scroll down to the “cookies” section. Next to “Allow cookies that are stored on your computer” select “Ask” to be notified or “Disable” to decline all cookies; 
  * In the Internet Explorer 6, 7 or 8 (Microsoft) browser: Select “Tools”, “Internet Options”, “Privacy”, then the level you wish to apply; 
  * In the Firefox browser: Click on “Tools” and select “Options”. In the “Privacy and security” tab, untick the box “Accept cookies from websites”; 
  * In the Chrome (Google) browser: Click “Customize and control Google Chrome” and select “Settings”. Under “Privacy and security”, click on “Content settings” and enable “Block third-party cookies".

**5\. YOUR RIGHTS / CONTACT**

In accordance with current regulations, you have the right to access, correct, delete and object to the use of your personal data. You also have a right to prior consent to marketing and to object to it under the applicable regulations. You can ask for your personal data to be sent to you and you have the right to give instructions for the use of your personal data after your death.  You can also ask for restriction of the data and/or make a claim to the CNIL (the French data protection agency). Please use the contact form (<https://www.total.com/en/formulaire-de-contact>) to make your request or send it to the following address

TOTAL S.A.  
Communication Department  
2 Place Jean Millier - La Défense 6  
92400 COURBEVOIE, France
